Adrian Penu

London ovidiu_penu@yahoo.com +447885 995674

I am an enthusiastic and responsible individual who enjoys working hard and is willing to learn new skills. I am composed, focused, detail oriented and I ensure that my work meets the highest standards. I have experience as a dental technician working in orthodontics, crown and bridge, removable prosthetics and CAD/CAM technology. I am GDC registered since 2015.

Work Experience

CAD Dental Technician

SmileLife

August 2020 to Present

- Responsible for creating orthodontic treatment plans using 3Shape OrthoAnalyzer and OnyxCeph software
- Offering support to the orthodontist or dentist on questions about the treatment plan
- In depth knowledge on all the steps of the process from preparation of the virtual impressions, the treatment set up, treatment review and printing
- Understanding the physics and limits of tooth movements with clear aligners and prescribing realistic treatments whilst maintaining a high standard
- Assessing case feasibility and liaising with different departments in finding the best orthodontic solutions for the patient
- Proposing ideas for procedures and processes to promote improved service, customer satisfaction and overall department improvements
- Applying orthodontic clinical concepts and translating them to the digital set up to meet the requirements of patients
- Training new CAD designers and reviewing their work
- Communicating with other team members to ensure the delivery of high quality work in a fast paced market.

CAD/CAM Dental Technician

Estetica Dental Lab - London October 2019 to August 2020

- Responsible for digitally designing and milling complex dental restorations (Zirconia crowns, copings, implant bridges, implant abutments, all-on-four metal substructures, provisional PMMA restorations) using ExoCad software.
- Guided surgery planning for dental practices and compiling detailed report plans
- 3D printing dental models and implant drilling guides
- Communicating with dentists throughout the treatment planning process and discussing solutions available to achieve the best result possible (angled/ straight implant screw channel, metal backings, B.O.P.T)
- Quality checking intraoral iTero scans and liaising with the surgeries to achieve a high fidelity scan of the patients mouth

- Communicating with milling centres to ensure the digital workflow is running smoothly (high turnaround, maintaining top quality standards, meeting deadlines)
- Learning new skills in a short period of time
- Adapting my skills to the technological requirements of the field
- Ensuring machines are well running and prevent any flaws
- Meeting standards demanded by our prestigious clients.

Dental Technician

Nimrodental - London

May 2016 to September 2019

- · Production of removable orthodontic appliances, clear aligners, orthodontic retainers
- Scanning models using 3Shape scanners and scanning dental impressions using CT scanner
- Correcting teeth misalignments using 3Shape Ortho Systems software
- Quality checking 3D printed dental models
- Training and supervising trainee dental technicians

Dental Technician

Hoil Dental - London

September 2015 to April 2016

- Responsible for digitally designing and milling complex dental restorations (Zirconia crowns, Ti based implant abutments, dental bars, bridges) using softwares such as ExoCad, 3Shape and Hyperdent.
- Learning new skills in a short period of time
- Adapting my skills to the technological requirements of the field
- Ensuring machines are well running and prevent any flaws
- Compiling reports of my weekly activities
- Presenting on different dental topics
- Meeting standards demanded by our prestigious clients.

Dental Technician

Associated Laboratories - London September 2013 to September 2015

- Responsible for manually sculpting and casting various dental prosthetics in the dental laboratory
- Digitally designing and milling restorations such as crowns, bridges and dental copings using Ceramill software
- Adhering to high standards
- Meeting strict deadlines
- Adapting to the company's work flow
- Working in a team
- · Motivating and instructing trainees

Trainee Dental Technician

Cedar Dental Laboratory - London October 2012 to August 2013

- Assisting dental technicians with their daily duties
- Casting plaster models and doing wax-up for bite registration blocks, partial dentures and special trays
- Learning new skills and thriving to be competent in the field
- Making sure that the laboratory is always tidy and in an organized state

• Delivering work to dental surgeries

Operations Manager

Hurlingham Property Services - London October 2010 to September 2012

- Management of cleaning teams and supervision of work quality
- Conducting interviews and recruiting
- Dealing with clients on a day to day basis
- Customer service and handling complaints
- · Motivating and people management

Education

Diploma in Level 3

Lambeth College 2012 to 2014

Baccalaureate Diploma in Mathematics and Computer Sciences

Petru Maior High School

2002 to 2006

Skills

- ExoCad
- 3Shape
- iTero
- RealGuide
- 3D printing
- inLab CAM
- Ceramill
- OnyxCeph
- · Fixed bonded retainer manufacturing
- Fixed dental restorations and prosthesis manufacturing
- Training and supervising trainee technicians
- · Dental implants
- Digitally designing all-on-4 substructures
- Clear aligner manufacturing
- Orthodontic treatment planning

Certifications and Licenses

GDC registration

June 2015 to Present

Additional Information

Languages: Hungarian(fluent), Romanian(fluent), English(fluent), Italian(basic), Arabic(reading)